free-url-submit.com 2003-04-09

# Free-URL-Submit.COM - Webmaster Tools

Free-URL-Submit.COM and SOHO-iT are committed to protecting consumer privacy online. We believe that greater protection of personal privacy on the Web will not only protect consumers, but also increase consumer confidence and ultimately their participation in online activities. At Free-URL-Submit.COM, we intend to give you as much control as possible over your personal information (individually identifiable information about an individual collected online) and strive to help you protect your privacy while using our services.

The purpose of our policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you when you visit our site, how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of such information and your ability to correct it. Please read this notice. By using this site, you signify your assent to our privacy policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site.

**I. Information Which We Collect and What We Do With the Collected Information**

We have three areas on our Web site: free services provided in our directory by Free-URL-Submit.COM, RobotPack and the Free-URL-Submit.COM Store, in which users can purchase services related to the general Web site. Each area has different privacy practices.

**a. General Web Site**

While visiting Free-URL-Submit.COM, you can be assured that no personal information is collected, retained or used by Free-URL-Submit.COM, 

_unless_ you voluntarily supply it or are visiting the Free-URL-Submit.COM Store and choose to purchase services. (See below for more details regarding information collected at the Free-URL-Submit.COM Store). If you choose to utilize certain interactive features on the Free-URL-Submit.COM site (including, but not limited to, sending e-mails, answering surveys, entering contests, using our free services or subscribing to newsletters), personal information may be requested from you. The personal information requested may include your e-mail address, postal address, name and, if you are purchasing product from the Free-URL-Submit.COM Store, your home or work telephone number and credit card number. You may be asked voluntarily to provide your income, job function, industry, age, gender or other demographic information; however, this information is not required to participate in online activities or to receive information from us. It is entirely your choice to determine whether or not you wish to submit any personal information. Free-URL-Submit.COM, with the exception of The Free-URL-Submit.COM Store, does not use "cookies" or tracking software that can identify you personally while you are visiting the site.

All submissions to the Free-URL-Submit.COM site become the property of SOHO-iT, which has the right to use them free of charge, and in any manner and in any medium, forever and throughout the world. This means that your submissions might appear in publications including, but not limited to, forums, newsletter or on a SOHO-iT Web site. If you do not want your submissions to become the property of SOHO-iT, please do not submit to our sites.

We use the personal information collected on our site for purposes such as correspondence, contacting winners of contests or providing you with a newsletter. There may be instances in which you will have the opportunity to subscribe to an e-mail list that will send information about the site or our advertisers to your e-mail address, but this will be done only with your permission and consent. Additionally, in each newsletter, you will be provided with the opportunity to opt out of receiving future correspondence. To subscribe or unsubscribe to The Free-URL-Submit.COM Newsletter please follow the instructions at [Free-URL-Submit.COM Newsletter](http://www.free-url-submit.com/). You can only enter the address you send your request from; you can't add other people's addresses to the mailing list. To unsubscribe from the Free-URL-Submit.COM e-mail, please follow the instructions at [Free-URL-Submit.COM Newsletter](http://www.free-url-submit.com/).

SOHO-iT and its affiliates (see sections II and IV) may perform statistical analyses of aggregate user behavior, but they are not based on personal information. These analyses allow SOHO-iT to measure relative consumer interest in the various areas of our Web sites for product and service development purposes. Any non-personally identifiable information collected is used for our own internal purposes to improve the content of the Web sites, to enhance users' experiences when visiting our site, to customize the content and/or layout of our pages and to provide the services required by an individual user. Again, any statistical analyses of user behavior will not be based on personal information, but solely on aggregate information. SOHO-iT may share this aggregate non-personally identifiable information with advertisers or potential advertisers.

Our site features several activities which are co-sponsored by other Web sites. We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of any of our co-sponsors and strongly recommend that you check their privacy policies. SOHO-iT does not own, control, have access to, or maintain any information collected by our co-sponsors.

Our site features several activities involving affiliate programs offered by other Web sites. We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of any of our affiliates and strongly recommend that you check their privacy policies. SOHO-iT does not own, control, have access to, or maintain any information collected by our affiliates.

Additionally, our site contains links to other Web sites, including those of advertisers. We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of advertisers or other sites to which we provide links from our site. For example, if you click on a banner advertisement, the click takes you off the Free-URL-Submit.COM site. These other sites (including co-sponsors, affiliates and advertisers) may use cookies, collect data or solicit personal information. We have no control over these practices and strongly recommend that you check the applicable privacy policy of the site to which you are linking. SOHO-iT does not own, control, have access to, or maintain any information collected by these other Web sites.

**b. The Free-URL-Submit.COM Store**

When you purchase services from Free-URL-Submit.COM, we will request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information, including your name, postal address, daytime and evening telephone numbers, credit card number and e-mail address. Free-URL-Submit.COM may supply this information to third parties, such as fulfillment houses, for the sole purpose of fulfilling your order. Individuals who do not have a Visa, MasterCard, Discover or American Express credit card are not permitted to purchase product online. 

When you purchase product from The Free-URL-Submit.COM Store, you are given the choice of opting out of receiving future e-mail solicitations from SOHO-iT about promotions and sales items that may be of interest to you. If you do not opt out, SOHO-iT will use this information only to send you e-mails regarding future promotions. Your personal information is not shared with third parties. All future e-mail solicitation will contain instructions on how to opt out of receiving additional e-mails. Participation in such mailings is entirely your choice.

**II. Use of Cookies**

What are cookies? Like many other commercial sites, our site may utilize a standard technology called a "cookie" to collect information about how our site is used. Cookies were designed to help a Web site recognize a user's browser as a previous visitor and thus save and remember any preferences that may have been set while the user was browsing the site. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on a computer virus or capture your e-mail address. SOHO-iT uses cookies in the Free-URL-Submit.COM Store to securely keep track of selections, such as those selected in a "shopping cart." 

SOHO-iT and its affliates' cookies help us see which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to our Web site are based on the data collected through the cookies such as total number of visitors and pages viewed. Cookies on our site may collect your domain name and track your selections through our Web pages. We only use "cookies" to gather the information indicated in this policy and do not use cookies to gather personal information about you without your consent. We may disclose the non-personally identifiable information collected, in aggregate form only, to third parties including advertisers or potential advertisers.

**III. Disclosure to Third Parties**

The personal information you choose to provide to us via submissions to our site (such as when you submit information about robots, messages in the Forums, surveys and so on, will be disclosed to visitors to the Free-URL-Submit.COM site. THEREFORE, IF YOU DO NOT WANT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO BE KNOWN BY OTHERS, DO NOT PARTICIPATE IN THESE TYPES OF ACTIVITIES.

We may disclose to our Administering Agencies personal information you voluntarily provide to us in order to participate in contests. These Administering Agencies use the information only for conducting the contest and retain the information only as long as is required by law and then destroy it.

Personal information you submit when you choose to purchase products or services from the Free-URL-Submit.COM Store (as described in Section I.b.) will be disclosed only to the fulfillment houses who use the information solely for processing your order. We disclose our statistical analyses or demographics of users to third parties, such as advertisers or potential advertisers, in aggregate form only.

SOHO-iT does not retain personal information in tracking profiles.

**IV. Advertising**

The advertising contained on Free-URL-Submit.COM is delivered to you by our affiliates. In the course of delivering an ad to you, we do not collect any personal information about you, such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail address. We do, however, use cookies (see Section II. for a discussion of "cookies") to collect non-personally identifiable information about you, such as the server your computer is logged on to, your browser type (for example, Netscape or Internet Explorer), and whether you responded to the ad delivered. This collection of information is commonly referred to as "tracking."

The non-personally identifiable information collected by us is used for the purpose of targeting ads and measuring ad effectiveness on behalf of advertisers and Web publishers who specifically request it. 

Free-URL-Submit.COM's policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond SOHO-iT's control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or government regulation.

**V. Accuracy of User Information**

In order to ensure the accuracy of personal information provided for purchase at the SOHO-iT Store, you may return to the order form online in order to change information you have provided prior to checking out. Questions regarding our privacy policy, the accuracy of your personal information or the use of the information collected should be directed via e-mail to [Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@free-url-submit.com), or you can reach us by telephone at 514-288-7646.

You can also write to us at:  
SOHO-iT  
Attn: Web Privacy Policy  
C.P. 539, Succ. Desjardins  
Montreal, QC  
H5B 1B6, Canada

These privacy policies are effective as of November 1, 2002. We reserve the right to change this policy at any time, and will post any changes to this policy as soon as they go into effect.

**VI. Security of Information**

We use our best efforts to ensure the security of personal information submitted by users. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of information from your PC to our computers. Unfortunately, no electronic communication over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to take great care to protect your personal information, Free-URL-Submit.COM and SOHO-iT cannot warrant the security of any information that you submit to us, and therefore it is understood that you do so at your own risk. When collecting credit card information for online purchases, we do offer secured-server transactions that encrypt your information in transit to thwart anyone from intercepting it and misusing it. We also store any personal information, including credit card numbers, in an area to which the general public does not have access.

Remember to sign off from the Free-URL-Submit.COM site and close your browser window when you are finished. This is to ensure that others cannot impersonate you online. This is especially important if you are at a terminal that is accessible to others, such as in a library, a school, at work or at an Internet cafe.
